# **Taufiq Mohammed**

Email: taufiqmmhd@gmail.com

LinkedIn: <a href="mailto:linkedin.com/in/taufigmmhd/">linkedin.com/in/taufigmmhd/</a>

Github: github.com/taufigmmhd

# Summary

I am an 18 year old student who spends most of my time on either the guitar or programming. One area that I am working on right now is web development. Additionally, I am pretty weak when it comes to backend development and would like to develop it more during an internship.

# Education

# Ngee Ann Polytechnic

Apr 2017 - Present

Diploma in Information Security & Forensics

- Cumulative GPA of 3.89 out of 4.0
- Expected to graduate in Apr 2020

# Work Experience

IHPC @ A\*STAR https://www.a-star.edu.sg/ihpc

Nov 2018 - Present

Full-stack Developer Intern

- Building a web platform to display and manage industrial applications of water pipe leakage
- Created backend for retrieval of sensor data

Android App Developer

Covve

Apr 2017 - Apr 2018

- Created an application for Sports SG staff members for incident reporting, announcements and handbook references
- Worked with Facebook to create a chatbot in Workplace (Tool by Facebook) to serve as an alternative to the app as well
- Learnt MVP architecture during this project

# Codigo <a href="https://www.codigo.co/">https://www.codigo.co/</a>

Jan 2017 - Apr 2017

Android App Developer Intern

- Built an app for people to learn how to swim through a range of videos and guizzes
- Learnt how to handle and send JSON payloads using Retrofit <a href="https://bit.ly/2YbayPn">https://bit.ly/2YbayPn</a>
- Worked with creative team to incorporate designs into the application

# Co-Curricular Activities

#### NullSec

Cyber security Special Interest Group in Ngee Ann Polytechnic

Vice President

May 2017 - Present

 Organized an inter-poly Capture The Flag (CTF) competition that involved all 5 polytechnics in Singapore

#### Overflow

Programming Special Interest Group in Ngee Ann Polytechnic

Member

May 2017 - Present

- Created workshop materials for students in StrITWise, a annual competition to expose secondary school students to the world of IT
- Hosted python workshops for secondary school students

#### **SST INC**

App development company and IT interest group

President

Apr 2015 - June 2016

- In charge of creating events such as camps and plans for the year
- Created an app (KKH PAN) to be a quick reference guide, emergency handbook and drug calculator for pediatric anesthesiologists in KK Women's & Children's Hospital

# Skills

## **Programming Languages**

Python, Javascript, Java, Kotlin, MySQL

#### **Frameworks**

React, Bootstrap, React Native, Django

# **Achievement**

Comptia Security+ Certification

## Referees

## **Aurelius Yeo**

Head of Department, Education Technology School of Science and Technology, Singapore 1 Technology Drive, Singapore 138572

## Lee Chin Seng

Senior Lecturer School of ICT, Ngee Ann Polytechnic 535 Clementi Rd, Singapore 599489